

abdulselam4246@gmail.com

+25193566424

Addis Abeba, Ethiopia

https://abdulselamt.github.io/portfolio/home.htr

https://github.com/abdulselamT

#### **Contact**

**~** [

Ethiopian



Date of birth 16/02/2000



Single

A Remote Python developer. Have 3+ years of experience in Python, data analysis, web automation, and Django development, and have participated in competitive programming. Also developed Telegram bots for several purposes. Specialize in backend development using Django and data analysis using pandas, numpy python libraries

## Work experience

## Volenteer Coordinator for National ETCPC ETCPC

## Adama, Ethiopia

From September 2020 to July 2023

I have honed my skills in event coordination and community engagement. I have successfully taught students the necessary skills to prepare for programming contests and efficiently coordinated programming contests, showcasing my ability to lead and motivate teams. I have demonstrated my commitment to fostering growt and development in the field of computer programming.

#### Web app developer Internship Unity University

from june 2021- august 2021

In my Internship period I have developed E-student  $% \left( 1\right) =1$  web app for secondary students . my role was from designing user interface and

API management

# Full-Stack Developer Freelance upwork

# since june 2022

Upwork is an online freelancing platform that connects businesses and individuals with independent professionals offering a wide range of services. I have developed telegram bots and plotting graph scripts

# **Education**

Bachelor Degree from Department of Computer Science and Engineering Adama Science and Technology University

Adama, Ethiopia

From September 2019 to July 2023

## **Social networks**



@aosqa



@aosqa



@aosga

# **Programming Language**

Python

4 years of professional experience in developing and skilled at solving programming challenges.

Javascript

2+ year Experienced for web development.

### **Databases**

**PostgreSQL** 

Used as a primary database for the

project i worked.

MySQL

Used as a primary database in my

some of previous work.

Redis

used as a cache layer database to boost performance and scale the projects

## **Frameworks**

Django

have utilized Django core features such as models, views, and templates. I have Iso used the Django REST framework for API development. Used many database pools like PGbouncer and Mysqlpool.

Used many caching tools.

React native

have developed ,mobile app soundplayer and

others

pandas

I have used pandas for data analysing and seaborn

for visualization

#### Languages

Amharic

Native | Professional

**English** 

Professional

1